Guide to the Cornell University Fine Arts Library records, 1872-1995.
Cornell University Fine Arts Library records, 1872-1995.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Cornell University. Fine Arts Library records, 1872-1995.
15-3-2284
Cornell University.Fine Arts Library.
1.4 cubic ft., 8 v.
Correspondence, photographs, drawings, bound volumes
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Records of the Fine Arts Library, 1962-1969; correspondence, 1945-1980; volumes with list of subject headings, catalogue by authors (2 v.), "Gift Book," "Classification System," storage record book, "Catalogue de la Bibliotheque d'Architecture," "References to Illustrations in the Architecture Library," and "Senior Seminary in Architectural Bibliography, 1915-1916." Also, photographs of the interior of the Fine Arts Library, book charge card, and invitation to a reception for the Cornell Journal of Architecture, n.d. Also, 1 drawing each of proposed renovations, 1974, 1977.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Records of the Fine Arts Library, 1962-1969; correspondence, 1945-1980; volumes with list of subject headings, catalogue by authors (2 v.), "Gift Book," "Classification System," storage record book, "Catalogue de la Bibliotheque d'Architecture," "References to Illustrations in the Architecture Library," and "Senior Seminary in Architectural Bibliography, 1915-1916." Also, photographs of the interior of the Fine Arts Library, book charge card, and invitation to a reception for the Cornell Journal of Architecture, n.d. Also, 1 drawing each of proposed renovations, 1974, 1977.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cornell University.; Cornell University.College of Architecture, Art, and Planning.
Subjects:
Art libraries--New York (State)--Ithaca.
Form and Genre Terms:
Architectural drawings.; Photographs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Volumes
Boxes 1, 3
Series II. Correspondence
Boxes 2-4
Series III. Photographs
Box 2
Series IV. Reports
Box 4
Series V. Miscellany
Box 2-4
Series VI. Exhibition Pamphlets
Box 5-7
Series VII. Gallery Programs
Box 8-10
Series VIII. New York Urban Planning
Box 10
Series IX. Architecture and Design
Box 10
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Volumes
  - Catalogue by authors, [1895] (Box 1)
  - Catalogue by authors, 19-- (Box 1)
  - College of Architecture librarians note book classification system, 19-- (Box 1)
  - Gift book, 1914-1927 (Box 1)
  - White Architecture Library, 1871 (Box 1)
  - References to Illustrations in the Architecture Library of the Cornell University, no date (Box 1)
  - FAL description in Handbook of Libraries, no date (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - A. D. White Book Fund, January 31,1964, April 6,1965 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - College of Architecture Library: List of subject headings as of September 1, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Fine Arts Books Storage (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Series II. Correspondence
  - Correspondence, 1944-1951 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: A-F, 1944-1948 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: G-Q, 1943-1947 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: R-T, 1942-1946 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: U-W, 1941-1946 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, January 1965 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, February 1965 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, March 1965 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, April 1965 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, May 1965 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, June 1965 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, July 1965 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, August 1965 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, September 1965 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, October 1965 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, November 1965 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, December 1965 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence, January-March 1966 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence, April-May 1966 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence, June-July 1966 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence, September-October 1966 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence, November-December 1966 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence, January-February 1967 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence, March-April 1967 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence, May-July 1967 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence, August-September 1967 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence, October-December 1967 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Correspondence, 1971-1973 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Correspondence, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Correspondence, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Correspondence, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Correspondence, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Correspondence, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Correspondence, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Correspondence, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Correspondence, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Correspondence, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Correspondence, 1959-1960 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Art Library (Sibley) Correspondence, 1948-1963 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1970-1977 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1977-1980 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1981-1988 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1989-1992 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1987-1990 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Series III. Photographs
  - FAL photographs, no date (Box 2, Folder 42)
- Series IV. Reports
  - Annual Reports, 1966-1977 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Annual Reports, 1977-1989 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Series V. Miscellany
  - Fine Arts Library (FAL), 1962 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - FAL, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - FAL, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - FAL, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Miscellany, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - FAL Misc., 1966-1967 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Fine Arts Expansion, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - FAL Expansion, 1964-1969 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Catalogue by subjects, 19-- (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 19th America Microfilming Project Brochure, 1987-1989 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Original Grant Proposal/Council on Library Resources (19th Century American Architectural Periodicals Research Project), 1964-1969 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - FAL Bibliographies, 1967-1969 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Serials Currently Received in the Planning Collection, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Committees, 1971-1985 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Classification Systems, 1973-1974 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Guidebook, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Monaghan Collection, no date (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Library Memos, no date (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Vertical File, no date (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Newspapers Clippings, 1975-2004 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Newspapers Clippings pertaining to the Plaster Casts, 1977-1978 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Series VI. Exhibition Pamphlets
  This series consists mainly of museum exhibition fliers and pamphlets, but also contains catalogues, magazines, newspaper clippings, budget reports, blank postcards, resumes, a book, and biographical information pertaining to the artists and architects on file. Some personal notes and autographs from the artists are included. The labeled contents range in date from 1929 to 2007, although many items are undated.
  - Art Students League-News, 1966-1983 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Artists-A, 1950-1990 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Artists-B, 1983-1993 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Artists-Ba-Be, May 1949; 1961-1979 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    Contains a signature and personal note from artist Judith Bernstein.
  - Artists-Bf-Bz, May 1941-Dec 1942; 1958-1990; 2004 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Contains a signature with a personal note from artist Jack Bosson.
  - Blum, Zevi, 1977; July 25, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    Contains only the first issue of The Cornell Review from Spring 1977 and a newspaper clipping about Blum.
  - Artists-C, 1948-1990 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    Contains biographical information about Alfred D. Crimi.
  - Calder, Alexander, Post 1971 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Colby, Victor, April 1964- November 1968 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Artists-D, 1960-1985 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    Contains biographical information about steel artist Aristides Demetrios.
  - Daly, Norman, February 13 -March 4, 1950; April 10-May 16, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Artists-E, 1961-1988 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    Contains several articles about Margery Edwards.
  - Artists-F, 1953-1989 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Fuller, R. Buckminster, 1957-1972 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Artists-G, 1937-1989 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    Contains biographical information about artist Josep Grau-Garriga.
  - Artists-H, 1943-1993 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    Contains a cover letter and portfolio from Fred Hurt Winston.
  - Huxtable, Ada Louise -Columns, July 16, 1972-October 25, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    Contains only newspaper columns by and about Ada Louise Huxtable.
  - Artists-I, October 14, 1961-2002 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Artists-J, August 8, 1950-November 28, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Artists-K, 1934-1994 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Klee, Paul, May 3, 1962-May 27, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Artists-L, 1944-1987 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Artists-M, January 1927-February 10, 2007 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Marsh, Reginald, Undated (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Mies Van Der Rohe, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    Contains biographical information and photos of completed projects.
  - Monet, Claude, 1943 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Moore, Henry, 1947 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Artists-N, March 1962-Nov 28, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Newman, Barnett, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 29)
    Barnett Newman- Thomas B. Hess -1969
  - Artists-O, May 5, 1953- 1986 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Artists-P, 1950-2003 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Pissarro, Camille, Undated (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Picasso, Pablo, 1955-1971 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Poor, Henry Varnum, 1940 (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Artists-R, 1991 -1933 or 1906 (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Artists-S: Sa-Sc, 1934-1994 (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - Artists-S: Sd-Sk, 1953-1986 (Box 7, Folder 37)
    Contains an autographed, limited edition of We The People by Joyce Cutler Shaw.
  - Artists-S: Sl-So, 1950-1987 (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - Artists-S: Sp-Sz, 1929; 1961-1993; 2007 (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - Artists-Seley, Jason, January 21st, 1971- 1983 (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - Artists-T, April 14, 1940; January 2, 1951-July 5, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 41)
    Contains a folder of 1960-1970 Taramind Fellowship artists whose surnames do not necessarily begin with "T."
  - Artists-U, February 1, 1966-March 30, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - Artists-V, April 24, 1951-December 23, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 43)
  - Arists-W, September 1937-March 2, 2008 (Box 7, Folder 44)
    Contains an exhibition pamphlet signed by artist Abraham Walkowitz.
  - Artists-Wayne, June, March 24, 1969 1978 (Box 7, Folder 45)
  - Arists-Y, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 46)
  - Artists-Z, 1962- May 5, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 47)
- Series VII. Gallery Programs
  This series contains gallery exhibition pamphlets, museum visitor guides, annual gallery magazines, newspaper clippings, prints, memoranda, catalogues, fact sheets about exhibits, and related but miscellaneous items. In many cases, the exhibit pamphlets are undated.
  - Associations-A, April 16, 1937-January 16, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Acquavella Galleries, October 21, 1982-November 24, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Akron Art Institute, March 11,1961-March 12, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Albany Institute of History and Art, January 3rd, 1945-July 9, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Albright-Knox Art Gallery, Nov 19, 1963-December 31, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Allentown (Pa.) Art Museum, November 1966-July 1967 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - All India Fine Arts and Crafts, February 23, 1950-1953 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - American Craft Museum, October 26, 1986-March 22, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - American Federation of Arts, 1957-1965 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - American Institute of Architects, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    Contains one pamphlet with the 1977 Distinguished Building Awards.
  - Andrew Dickson White Museum of Art, 1963-1972 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    Contains an overview of the Andrew Dickson White Museum from 1963-1964.
  - Antwerpen Academie voor Schone Kunsten, November 22, 1958-August 12, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Antwerpen Nationaal Hoger Instituut, April 5, 1959-1963 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Archives of American Art, 1981-spring 1992 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Art Institute of Chicago, December 9, 1987-March 6, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Art Students League-Catalogue, June 3, 1985-August 23, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Arts Club of Chicago, February 15, 1961-September 28, 1961 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Asia Society, 1986-June 28, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Associated Amerian Artists, October 10, 1966-October 29, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Associations-B, November 16, 1955-May 23, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Baltimore Museum of Art, February 3, 1939-February 15, 1959; 2003-2004 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Bertha Schaefer Gallery, September 17, 1951-April 23, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Betty Parsons Gallery, 1952(?)-March 38, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Boston Institute of Contemporary Art, 1954-March 28, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Brandeis University Rose Art Museum, September 13, 1961-1963 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Brooklyn Museum, January 12, 1977-August 23, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Brooks Memorial Art Gallery, Memphis, September 1964-February 28, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Associations-C, 1941-March 18, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - California University-Berkeley University Art Gallery, 1960-August 22, 1961 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Canadian Center for Architecture, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Colby College Art Museum, 1959-1963 (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Columbus Gallery of Fine Arts, 1946-January 25, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Columbia University School of Architecture, Apr-82 (Box 8, Folder 33)
    The Magazine of Columbia University
  - Cornell University-Festival of Contemporary Art, April 28, 1949-May 1, 1955 (Box 8, Folder 34)
    Describes exhibitions in Memorial Room of Willard Straight Hall, Morse Hall, White Hall, and various other Cornell buildings.
  - Cornell University-Franklin Hall, May 6, 1963-May 11, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 35)
    Contains an exhibit (pencils, etchings, oil paintings) of Cornell University graduate Gillian Pederson-Krag in the Franklin Hall Gallery.
  - Cornell University-Martha van Rensselaer Gallery, 1952-January 11, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 36)
    Contains Martha van Rensselaer Gallery exhibition calendars for the years 1952-1954 and 1965-1967, along with specific exhibition pamphlets.
  - Cornell University-Willard Straight Hall, 1941-1946 (Box 8, Folder 37)
    Contains catalogues of an exhibition for water colors, an exhibition of student work, a local artists show, contemporary American drawings, war posters from 1914-1920, lithographs, wood sculptures, British watercolors, and a Cornell University faculty show in 1946.
  - Curt Valentine Gallery, November 20, 1951-June 8, 1955 (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - Associations-D, 1962-1988 (Box 8, Folder 39)
  - Dallas Museum of Fine Arts, 1978-2009 (Box 8, Folder 40)
  - Dartmouth College-Carpenter Art Galleries, May-June 1959 (Box 8, Folder 41)
  - Dayton Art Institute, March 5, 1948-January 8, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 42)
  - Durand-Ruel Galleries, March 27, 1940-April 13, 1940 (Box 8, Folder 43)
  - Associations-E, October 5, 1964-November 7, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 44)
    Contains one exhibition booklet from the Watson Art Gallery at Elmira College.
  - Everson Museum of Art, March 4, 1967-April 16, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 45)
  - Associations-F, March 21st, 1951-October 9, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 46)
    "55 Mercer" is filed here.
  - Fine Arts Society, London, June 26, 1968-June 25, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 47)
  - Florida State University, February 12, 1964-February 18, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 48)
  - Florida University-Grainesville, October 23, 1975-December 15, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 49)
  - Frances Lehman Loeb Art Center-Vassar College, August 22, 2008-2010 (Box 8, Folder 50)
  - Freer Gallery of Art, Washington, February 25, 1956 (Box 8, Folder 51)
  - Frick Collection, 1986-undated (Box 8, Folder 52)
  - Associations-G, February 1, 1967-January 22, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 53)
  - George Peabody College, April 22, 1961-May 17, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 54)
  - Gerson (Otto) Gallery, January 11, 1958-July 1962 (Box 8, Folder 55)
    In the "Monumental Sculpture" booklet on page 9 is the sculpture "Song of the Vowels" by Jacques Lipchitz, 1931-1932, which is now in front of Cornell's Uris Library.
  - Guggenheim Museum, February 11, 1989-June 16, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 56)
  - Associations-H, October 16, 1961-April 3, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 57)
  - Hamilton College-Edward W. Root Art Center, September 12, 1965-October 10, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 58)
    Contains a pamphlet for an exhibition of art by Cornell University faculty.
  - Harmon Foundation, January 6, 1928-May 4, 1935 (Box 8, Folder 59)
  - Herron Art Institute, Ind, 1943-March 26, 1967 (Box 9, Folder 60)
  - Hirschl and Adler Galleries, 1964, June, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 61)
  - Hirshhorn Museum-Smithsonian, December 1974-January 1975 (Box 9, Folder 62)
  - Historical American Buildings Survey, Undated (Box 9, Folder 63)
  - Historic Urban Plans, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 64)
    Contains a catalogue of historic city plan facsimiles available for purchase.
  - Houston Museum of Fine Arts, October 3, 1966- February 1972 (Box 9, Folder 65)
  - Howard University Gallery of Art, October 1961-April 28, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 66)
  - Associations-I, December 5, 1961-2001 (Box 9, Folder 67)
    Contains exhibition booklet signed by Bertha Urdang.
  - IBM Gallery, May 21, 1962-March 24, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 68)
  - IBM Gallery of Science and Art, July 22, 1986-April 27, 1999 (Box 9, Folder 69)
  - Institute for Architecture and Urban Studies, October 30, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 70)
  - Insituto de Diseno Rosario, Argentina, December 1961 (Box 9, Folder 71)
  - International Centre for the Study of the Preservation and Restoration of Cultural Property, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 72)
  - Isabella Stewart Gardner Museum Fenway Court, 1940 (Box 9, Folder 73)
  - Ithaca College Museum of Art, April 4, 1967-September 19,1971 (Box 9, Folder 74)
  - Associations-J, November 24, 1982-April 8, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 75)
  - Johnson Museum-Cornell University, 2002-2003 (Box 9, Folder 76)
  - Kansas University Museum of Art, May 1951 October 31, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 77)
  - Kennedy Galleries, January 1970-March 1970 (Box 9, Folder 78)
  - Kentucky University Art Gallery, June 12, 1961-November 26, 1967 (Box 9, Folder 79)
  - Kootz Gallery, October 3, 1950-October 17, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 80)
  - Kresge Art Museum, November 1969-2002 (Box 9, Folder 81)
  - Associations-L, March 24, 1964-December 1966 (Box 9, Folder 82)
  - Library of Congress, undated (Box 9, Folder 83)
  - Los Angeles County Museum of Art, 1958-March 13, 1966 (Box 9, Folder 84)
  - Louisville, University of-Allen R. Hite Art Institute, May 15, 1965-December 31, 1966 (Box 9, Folder 85)
  - Associations-M, 1938-1993 (Box 9, Folder 86)
  - Marburger Index, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 87)
  - Margaret Woodbury Strong Museum, Rochester, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 88)
  - Marlborough Fine Art, London, December 1962-January 1963 (Box 9, Folder 89)
  - Marlborough, New York, December 1970 (Box 9, Folder 90)
  - Maryland Institute College of Art, 1967-1971 (Box 9, Folder 91)
  - Massachusetts University-Amherst, February 6, 1966-February 24, 1967 (Box 9, Folder 92)
  - Metropolitan Museum of Art, N.Y., 1920; May 14, 1975-January 8, 1995 (Box 9, Folder 93)
  - Milwaukee Art Center, February 23, 1951-June 1967 (Box 9, Folder 94)
  - Miscellaneous ads, letters, and printed material, 1963-1994 (Box 9, Folder 95)
    This folder contains an assortment of promotional ads and pamphlets, along with material concerning the improvement and maintenance of towns, from artchitecural renderings to landmark conservation information. Receipts, letters, and the libretto Capriccio by Richard Strauss are also enclosed.
  - Montclair (NJ) Art Museum, January 3, 1950-1955 (Box 9, Folder 96)
  - Montreal Museum of Fine Arts, undated (Box 9, Folder 97)
  - Munson-Williams-Proctor Institute, October 1953-March 24, 1957 (Box 9, Folder 98)
  - Musee d'Orsay, September 1987 (Box 9, Folder 99)
  - Museum of American Folk Art, April 13, 1989-July 16, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 100)
  - Museum of Modern Art (MOMA), NY, 1944-1956; 1972-1995 (Box 9, Folder 101)
  - Associations-N, August 27, 1978-February 27, 1987; 2009 (Box 9, Folder 102)
  - National Academy of Design, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 103)
  - National Association of Women Artists, 1965-1967 (Box 9, Folder 104)
  - National Collection of Fine Arts, Smithsonian, January 17, 1966-January 1977 (Box 9, Folder 105)
  - National Endowment for the Arts, 1973-1978 (Box 9, Folder 106)
  - National Gallery of Art, Washington, March 17, 1948 -February 24, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 107)
  - National Museum of American Art, Undated (Box 9, Folder 108)
    Information about the inventory of American Sculpture and research resources in the Library of the National Museum of American Art is enclosed.
  - National Portrait Gallery, Washington, January 1977 (Box 9, Folder 109)
  - New Jersey State Museum, March 18, 1967-April 26, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 110)
  - New Museum of Contemporay Art, December 9, 1990-March 16, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 111)
  - New York State Council on the Arts, June 13, 1967 (Box 9, Folder 112)
    Two of three items are without a date.
  - New York University, 1960s (undated) (Box 9, Folder 113)
  - Associations-O, 1970-January 13, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 114)
    Includes profiles of the 32 Masters of Fine Arts Graduates of the Otis Art Institute class of 1970.
  - Associations-P, September 28, 1949-December 18, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 115)
    Contains an annotated 1953 exhibition and price catalogue.
  - Pennslyvania Academy of Fine Arts, 1910 (Box 10, Folder 116)
    Contains an "Eigth Annual Philadephia Water Color Exhibition Catlogue" from 1910.
  - Pennslyvania State University, October 26, 1969-June 5, 1970 (Box 10, Folder 117)
  - Philbrook Art Center, October 1951-April 30, 1959 (Box 10, Folder 118)
  - Pierport Morgan Library, November 17, 1988-May 6, 1990 (Box 10, Folder 119)
  - Queens Museum of Art, May 23, 2000-October 1, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 120)
  - Associations-R, March 17, 1994-June 12, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 121)
  - Associations-S, January 6, 1988-February 9, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 122)
  - S. Bitter-Larkin Gallery, April 5, 1990-May 12, 1990 (Box 10, Folder 123)
  - Smithsonian Institute-National Museum of Design, June 7, 1977-September 23, 1990 (Box 10, Folder 124)
  - Storm King Art Center, Undated (Box 10, Folder 125)
  - Tate Gallery, July 1987 (Box 10, Folder 126)
  - Tibor de Nagy Gallery-New York, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 127)
  - Associations-W, October 28, 1981- February 13, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 128)
  - Grants/Foundations, 2002 (Box 10, Folder 129)
- Series VIII. New York Urban Planning
  This series contains historical information and urban planning information about cities and towns in New York state. The contents include town museum pamphlets and booklets, pamphlets with city walking tours often focusing on architecture, information about historical museums, and newspaper clippings about construction and restoration projects.
  - Adirondacks, undated (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Auburn, 1951 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Canandaigua, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Cooperstown-Ostego Co., August 1967-1985 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Danby, NY, January 22, 1974-March 11, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Geneva, NY, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Groton, May 2, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Hamilton, NY, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Historic Ithaca-Miscellaneous Pubs, November 14, 1966- September 26, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Historic Ithaca-Newsletter, 1972-1993 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Ithaca Buildings, September 25, 1962- October 13, 1990 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    Though most of these articles concern restoration and demolition of public buildings, this file also contains Cornell-related articles that do not focus on Ithaca buildings.